Walassi Silva

Fullstack Web Developer | HTML | CSS | JavaScript | React | TypeScript | Styled Components | Tailwind | Express | Node.js | PostGreSQL | Git/ GitHub

Vespasiano/MG / Brazil (31) 98648-2092

walassi.b@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/walassi-silva github.com/WalassiSilva

Objective

To work in the Web Development field, utilizing the skills I have been enhancing in React, TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Tailwind, Node.js, SQL, API.

Summary

I'm Walassi, and I'm an extremely dedicated and committed individual when it comes to work. I have been enhancing my skills in web development, focusing on technologies such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Tailwind, Styled Components, SASS, Git/GitHub, Node.js, SQL, PostGreSQL, Prisma ORM, Jest, and Express.

I am transitioning from a different field; I spent 5 years working in an Tapestry business, where I gained a lot of real-world knowledge that isn't taught in classrooms. Skills such as quick reaction to unexpected situations, handling clients in stressful moments, and reallocating team and priorities when necessary.

My clear objective is to become a high-quality developer. I aim to be a professional capable of creating and participating in projects that bring about meaningful changes in people's lives, projects that facilitate, improve, and assist users, clients, and other stakeholders.

Education

• High School - E.E Deputado Renato Azeredo January 2012 - December 2014

Courses

 Dev Quest – FullStack Web Development Duration: 90h. Conclusion: December/2023

• Fundação Bradesco – C#

 Duration: 13h. Conclusion: June/2022
 Soul Code – Lógica de Programação Duration: 40h. Conclusion: January/2022

Languages

English: Intermediate/Advanced

Português: Navite

Experience

Tapeçaria Fernando Martins - Office Assistant and Financial Assistant May 2018 - June 2023.

Responsabilities:

- Prepare and send monthly closing reports to business partners
- Process payroll

- Sell carpet restoration services
- Conduct carpet screening and forwarding
- Manage route logistics

Diorges Oliveira Martins LTDA - Administrative Manager January 2024 - Current. Responsabilities:

- Organize the team and define tasks
- Maintain relationships with business partners
- Prepare and send monthly closing reports to business partners
- Process payroll
- Sell services via calls, messages, and home visits
- Conduct carpet screening and forwarding
- Manage route logistics

Hard Skills

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- React
- Tailwind
- Api
- Styled Component
- TypeScript
- Jest
- Node.js
- SQL
- C#
- Java
- Git/GitHub
- Word
- Excel

Projects

Money Manager

A Fullstack application created from scratch (Front-end, Back-end, API, Database) up to deployment with the main features of a paid financial manager.

It allows creating, editing, deleting transactions, categorizing by date, type, searching, viewing assets, and dynamic charts.

Technologies: TypeScript, Node.js, Express, PostGreSQL, Prima ORM, React.ts, React Router Dom, Tailwind.

Repo:

• Pass.in Node.js Api

Pass.in is a Node.js API for managing in-person events with attendees registration, check-in, and badge generation.

It allows to create an event with a name, description, and attendees limit; Register attendees;

List all attendees of a given event;

Check in attendees;

Generate a badge for each attendees;

Technologies: TypeScript, Fastify, Zod, Prisma, Swagger, SQLite.

Repo:

• Pokedex Api

This application uses the Pokemon API to fetch and display both general and detailed information about Pokemon. Users can search for a Pokemon by name or id, filter by name or type, view the list of Pokemon, and switch between light and dark themes.

Technologies: React, React Router Dom, Styled Components, Context Api, PokeApi.

Repo: Page:

Portfolio (React + Sass)

Portfolio summarizing my journey focusing on web development. It allows you to learn a bit about who I am, my contact networks, what I have studied, and some of the projects I have worked on.

Technologies: React + Vite, Sass.

Repo: Page:

GitHub Users API (API, HTML, CSS e JS)

This project is designed to retrieve user information from the GitHub platform through the API. Upon conducting the search, it returns the user's name, photo, bio, followers, following, repositories in link format, and information about them.

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, GitHub API

Repo: Page:

Soft Skills

- Teamwork;
- Commitment;
- Flexibility;

- Effective Communication;Problem-solving skills;Focus;

- Dedication;
- Punctuality;Emotional intelligence